‎NETFLIX 出品
‎你觉得我打偏了吗
You think I missed?
‎瞧…
Well…
‎打偏了10厘米
Off by four inches. …for the generator.
‎嘿 你干什么 这些是我要买的
Hey, what do you think you're doin'? I wanted those.
‎好的 卢
Gotcha, Lou.
‎…还有所谓的支付赎金
…and alleged ransom payments.
‎我们过去没有 ‎我重复一遍 没有通过武器交易
We did not, repeat, did not trade weapons
‎或其他方式来交换人质 ‎将来也不会这样做
or anything else for hostages, nor will we.
‎里根总统谈及与伊朗的紧张关系
President Reagan addressing the heightened tensions with Iran in the country's 1953 coup.
‎嘿 卢
-Hey, Lou.
‎其他新闻 罗杰斯委员会的报告
In other news, pages from the Rogers Commission's report
‎调查了太空穿梭机挑战者号灾难 ‎让美国宇航局备受抨击…
on the Space Shuttle Challenger disaster, with NASA under fire…
‎你为大风暴做好准备了吗
You, uh, ready for the big storm?
‎我要提款
Makin' a withdrawal.
‎今天要取多少钱
And, uh, how much will you be taking out today?
‎有多少取多少
Ah, whatever's in there.
‎哦
Oh.
‎好的
Okay.
‎…没有伊朗的配合
Without Iran's cooperation,
‎我们无法结束波斯湾战争
we cannot bring an end to the Persian Gulf War.
‎没有伊朗的…
Without Iran's…
‎那…是很大一笔钱呢
-There's a lot of money.
‎我知道啊
I know.
‎钱就是我存进去的
I'm the one who put it in there.
‎如果您想打电话 ‎请先投币25美分 然后再拨号
If you'd like to place a call, please deposit 25 cents before dialing.
‎如需帮助 请挂断后重新致电
If you need help, please hang up and try your call again.
‎兰金
Rankin.
‎下午好 卢
Afternoon, Lou.
‎贾克斯心情很好嘛
Jax is in a good mood.
‎我不禁在想 ‎是不是因为打猎很刺激
Can't help but wonder if the spark of the hunt
‎所以才让它兴奋得不行
hasn't got him all worked up.
‎不太可能 现在不是打猎的季节
Unlikely. It isn't hunting season.
‎哦
Oh.
‎那鹿一定是突然冒出来的
Deer must have just bolted out of nowhere.
‎迅雷不及掩耳
Happened so fast.
‎我很高兴你和贾克斯安全出来了
Well, I'm glad you and Jax came out of it okay.
‎你应该给自己买一条铜手链
You know, you ought to get yourself one of these copper bracelets.
‎-漂亮 ‎-我侄女在大陆给我买的
-Pretty. -My niece got it for me on the mainland.
‎其中一个装着好梦安睡环
One of those stores, you know,
‎还有水晶之类的东西
with the dream catchers and crystals and whatnot.
‎我还笑她来着 但我对天发誓 ‎现在我的关节炎好多了
-I laughed at her. But I swear to God, I barely feel the arthritis anymore.
‎我又开始钓鱼了
I'm fishin' again.
‎戴着这玩意儿小心别被雷劈了
Careful you don't get struck by lightning wearin' that thing.
‎早上好 卢
-Oh, that's right. Mornin', Lou!
‎我喜欢…
I love--
‎这是恶劣天气预警
This is a severe weather watch.
‎西北太平洋近年来最大的一次风暴
The biggest storm the Pacific Northwest has seen in years
‎预计将于今天入夜后来袭
is expected to make landfall early this evening.
‎请各位居民尽量待在家里
Residents are encouraged to stay in their homes
‎做好准备 届时会出现电力中断 ‎低洼地区会有洪涝
and be prepared for downed power lines and flooding in low-lying areas.
‎开往圣胡安群岛的渡轮也已暂停服务
Ferry service to the San Juan Islands has also been suspended
‎重开时间另行通知
until further notice
‎因为风暴将直接吹袭本区域
as the area is directly in the storm's path.
‎她跑哪儿去了呢 我不知道
Where could she be? I don't know.
‎她不在这棵树下
She's not under this tree.
‎（价真五金店）
‎她不在这里
She's not over here.
‎她藏得真好啊
Oh, she's so good at hiding.
‎一定得找到她
Gotta find her.
‎也许她在里面
Maybe she's inside.
‎好 我去那里看看
Yeah, I'm gonna check there.
‎抓到你啦
-I got you! -I got you! I got you!
‎你都没有说“小兔子”的暗号
-You didn't say the code! Little Rabbit.
‎再来一次嘛
One more time.
‎不行
-No.
‎求你了
-Please.
‎我说了不行 小薇 来吧
I said no, Vee. Come on.
‎把钉子递给我
Pass me a nail?
‎谢谢
Thanks.
‎妈妈 你觉得 ‎爸爸会很快找到宝藏吗
Mom, do you think Daddy's gonna find the treasure soon?
‎已经两年了
It's been two years.
‎我不知道 小薇 他应该很快会找到的
I don't know, Vee. I bet he's real close.
‎那爸爸会回家吗
And then is Daddy gonna come home?
‎知道吗 风暴似乎还要过会儿才来
You know, the storm looks like it's a while away.
‎我们或许可以再玩一次躲猫猫
We could probably fit in another game.
‎我打赌你撑不过三分钟 ‎就会被我找到了
I bet you can't make it past three minutes before I find you, though.
‎-我可以的 ‎-我觉得你撑不过
-Oh, I can. -Oh, I don't think you can.
‎好吧 我看看 准备好了吗 预备…
All right. Let me see. Ready? Set…
‎-游戏开始 ‎-游戏开始
-Game on! -Game on!
‎一
One…
‎二
two…
‎三
three…
‎四
four…
‎五 六
five… six…
‎七…
Seven…
‎-嘿 卢 ‎-房租 明天
-Hey, Lou. -Rent. Tomorrow.
‎我知道 听我说 ‎我得为风暴准备食品物资
I know. Listen, now, I had to lay in supplies for the storm.
‎-能不能… ‎-不能延期
-So I was wondering whether-- -No extensions.
‎好吧
-All right.
‎明天 把钱放在里面桌子上
-Tomorrow. Inside. On the table.
‎-不然放在信箱里会弄湿的 ‎-钱会付给你的
It'll get wet in the mailbox. You'll get it.
‎小薇
Vee!
‎你这人是怎么回事
What the hell is wrong with you?
‎明知道附近有小孩 ‎你为什么还要开这么快
Why you gotta drive so goddamn fast? You know there's a child nearby.
‎这世界不是游乐场 ‎教你的孩子要自己小心
World's not a playground. Teach your kid to look out for herself.
‎来吧 贾克斯
Come on, Jax.
‎-嘿 ‎-进去吧
-Hey. -Go inside.
‎-妈妈  ‎-小薇 进去吧
-No, Mom! -Vee, go inside.
‎没事吧
-Everything o-- okay?
‎别跺脚 小姑娘
And no stomping, little girl.
‎不 不用了 谢谢你 克里斯
-No. We're fine. Thanks, Chris.
‎-你还好吗  ‎-还好 我只是累了
-You doin' all right? -Yeah, I'm just tired.
好吧
All right.
卢还在让你烦恼吗
Is Lou still bein' a pain in your ass?
‎我跟你说过这事
-I told you about that?
‎是啊
-Yeah.
‎-你不记得了 我们… ‎-不记得了
Yeah, you don't… you don't remember? -No.
‎听我说 我们当时都喝醉了
-Look, we were both pretty drunk, so…
‎-是啊 ‎-对 显然如此
-Yeah. Yeah. -Clearly,
‎因为我都不记得我说过了
'cause I… I don't remember that.
‎我记得你使出了吃奶的劲儿 ‎在唱“宛如处女”
I do remember you singing "Like A Virgin" at the top of your lungs.
‎请你发誓不告诉别人
Oh, please swear you'll never tell.
‎不然呢
Or what?
‎我不知道
I don't know.
‎不然…
Or, uh…
‎妈 我找不到河马先生
Mom! I can't find Mr. Hippo!
‎我得走了
Listen, I gotta go.
‎嘿 你有没有…
Hey, have you, um…
‎妈 帮我找把它找出来
-Mom, help me find him.
‎你找机会跟小薇谈过了吗
Have you had a chance to talk to Vee yet?
‎关于她爸的事
About her dad?
‎你没事吧
You all right?
‎-我能搭个便车吗  ‎-当然可以 上车吧
-Any way I could get a ride? -Yeah, of course. Get in here. -Thank you.
‎倒霉的租赁车坏掉了 ‎你真是帮了我一个大忙
Sorry about that. Oh, damn rental car broke down on me. You're a lifesaver.
‎天啊 我把你的座位都弄湿了
Oh, jeez, I'm-- I'm gettin' your seat all soaked.
‎别担心 得亏是我开车经过看见了你
Don't worry about it, man. I'm just glad I passed you when I did.
‎风暴天会很危险
The storm's gonna be gnarly.
‎（《论死亡与临终》）
‎好深奥啊
Heavy reading.
‎对 给我一个朋友买的
Yeah, I bought it for a friend of mine.
‎她的前夫三个月前去世了 ‎她很难接受现实 所以…
Her ex died three months ago, and she's just-- she's havin' a hard time facin' it.
‎明白了 你想帮她面对现实吧
I see. And you wanna help her face it, right? Hm?
‎-因为你想比做朋友更进一步  ‎-不 听我说 我只是…她有个孩子
'Cause you wanna be more than just friends? Oh, look, I just-- She has a kid.
‎她想慢慢来
She wants to take it slow.
‎哦 我喜欢这个乐队
Oh! I love this band.
‎-杰夫波卡罗是个很厉害的人 ‎-哦 是的 他是最棒的
Oh, Jeff Porcaro's the man. -Oh, yeah. He's the best.
‎搞什么 操
Fuck! What the fuck?
‎（大学资金）
‎（爸爸 小薇）
‎小薇
Vee…
‎小薇 看着我
Vee, look at me.
‎你之前问过爸爸的事 对吧
You know when you were asking about Daddy earlier?
‎怎么说呢…
Well, um…
‎宝贝 他…
Baby, he, um…
‎他很爱你
He loves you so much.
‎他心里一直在挂念你
And he thinks about you all the time.
‎你在做什么呢
What are we making?
‎-友谊手链 ‎-哦
-Friendship bracelets. -Oh.
‎我想做一条友谊手链
I wanna make a friendship bracelet.
‎这个是给卢的
This one is for Lou.
‎你在给卢做手链 为什么
You're making a bracelet for Lou? Why?
‎我喜欢卢
I like Lou.
‎我知道你不喜欢
-I know you don't.
‎不 我喜欢啊
-Yeah, I do.
‎好吧 我其实不喜欢卢 ‎但是你为什么喜欢她呢
Okay. I actually don't like Lou. But why do you like her?
‎因为贾克斯喜欢她 而我喜欢贾克斯
Well, Jax likes her, and I like Jax.
‎哦
Oh.
‎我向来不是话多的人 ‎我就长话短说了
"I've never been one for many words, so I'll keep this short."
‎房子归你了 拿去卖掉吧
"The house is yours. Sell it."
‎冰箱的肉够贾克斯吃一个月 ‎还有给你一些现金
"There's a month's worth of meat for Jax in the freezer, and some cash for you."
‎我做的一些决定 你永远都不会理解
"There are certain decisions I made that you will never understand."
‎但那都是过去的事了
"But that's all in the past now."
‎人生可能会很残酷
"Life can be cruel."
‎有些事我很擅长 ‎但有些事我做得一塌糊涂
"What made me great at some things made me lousy at others."
‎我希望我能说 ‎自己的所作所为带来了好的结果
"I wish I could say that some good came from what I did."
‎事实上
"In truth,
‎我让世界变成了更危险的地方
I left the world a more dangerous place."
‎现在该睡啦 好了
-Bedtime, now!
‎-河马先生  ‎-我累坏了
-Mr. Hippo! -I'm exhausted.
‎来吧 河马先生 晚安
Come on, Mr. Hippo. -Good night.
‎我好热
-I'm hot.
‎我也很热 ‎但很快就凉快了 因为下雨了
Yeah, now I'm hot too. But you'll be cold soon because it's raining.
‎只是风而已 宝贝 别害怕
Oh, it's just the wind, baby. Don't be scared.
‎我没有怕
-I'm not scared.
‎-好的 ‎-你害怕吗
-Okay. -Are you scared?
‎-你今晚想跟我睡吗  ‎-如果你想 我就跟你睡
-Do you wanna sleep with me tonight? -Oh, if you need me to, I will.
‎我想让你跟我睡
-I think I do.
‎该死
Oh shit.
Shit, shit, shit, shit!
‎小薇
-Vee…
‎-说话注意点 ‎-该死
-Watch your mouth. -Shit!
‎我要去把断电器打上去
I'm just gonna go flip the breaker.
‎我马上回来 好吗
I'll be right back, okay?
‎妈妈
Mommy?
‎是你吗
Is that you?
‎克里斯
Chris!
‎小薇
Oh! Vee!
‎不 小薇
No! Vee!
‎小薇
Vee!
Vee! Vee! Vee! Vee? Vee!
‎-电话呢  ‎-搞什么鬼
-Where's your phone? -What the hell?
‎该死的电话在哪 我得打给警长
Where's your goddamn phone? I gotta call the sheriff.
‎-妈的 操  ‎-别急 出什么事了
-God damn it! Fuck! -Slow down. What happened?
‎小薇不见了
-Vee's gone.
‎你又让她跑开了 她走不了多远
-What, you let her wander off again? -She's not gonna get far in this.
‎不 她爸爸把她带走了
-No, no, no. -Her father took her.
‎她爸爸
-Her father?
‎他来了 他怎么会在这里
He's… he's here. How the hell is he here?
‎等等 你看到他了吗
Hold on. You saw him?
‎没有 我…
No. I…
‎他应该是死了 但是他找到了我们
He… he's supposed to be dead, but he found us.
‎我以为摆脱他了
I-- I thought we were free of him.
‎他还杀了克里斯
-He killed Chris.
‎天啊
-Jesus Christ.
‎你的钥匙呢  ‎车子发动不了 我得去找警长
Where are your keys? The car won't start. I gotta get to the sheriff.
‎-我来开车 ‎-好
-I'll drive. -Okay.
‎糟了
Hm.
‎快点
-No, no, no, no, no! Come on!
‎-怎么了  ‎-快跑
-What's wrong? -Run!
‎怎么了
What?
‎趴下
Down!
‎你怎么知道会爆炸
Ho-- how did you know it was gonna blow up?
‎炸弹就是会爆炸
Bombs tend to.
抱歉 伙计
Sorry about that, buddy.
结果我还没做完
Turns out I'm not done yet.
‎炸弹 卢 ‎这说明他一直在计划这件事
A bomb? It means he's been plannin' this, Lou.
‎我们需要更多支援 我们得去找警长
We gotta get more help. We need to get to the sheriff.
‎没法去找他 没有车 电话也坏了
Can't get to him. No cars. Phones are down.
‎我们在城外十几公里
We're ten miles outside of town.
‎每耽误一秒 ‎你孩子就走远一步 我得去追踪他们
Your kid's gettin' further away by the second. I have to track 'em.
‎什么
What?
‎你追踪他们
Track 'em? You?
‎去拿电池 在厨房
Get batteries. Kitchen.
‎你不了解情况 菲利普以前当过兵
You don't understand. Philip was a Green Beret.
‎他在中美洲做了可怕的事 ‎因此还被通缉了
Wanted for some terrible shit that he did in Central America.
‎是战争罪什么的
War crimes kind of shit.
‎我看了法庭手稿 他折磨俘虏来作乐
I saw the court transcripts. He was torturing hostages for fun.
‎他训练有素
He's highly trained.
‎是个炸弹专家 ‎妈的 我们可不是他的对手
An explosives expert. Well, we're no match for him, Lou.
‎我们需要专业的救援 ‎光凭你和你家狗是不行的
We need professional help. You and the dog ain't gonna cut it.
‎他从你的拖车里拿走了什么吗
Did he take anything from your trailer?
‎拿走了小薇最喜欢的 ‎河马先生玩偶 还有一条毯子
Her-- her favorite stuffy, Mr. Hippo. -And a-- a blanket.
‎他想让她舒服一点
-He wants her comfortable.
‎他只想让她保持安静
He wants her quiet.
‎正在翻修
Renovations.
‎警察试图逮捕他时 ‎他炸毁了自己的公寓
When they tried to arrest him, he blew his apartment up.
‎警察也发了死亡证明 ‎他怎么可能还活着
They sent a death certificate. How the hell could he still be alive?
‎氟烷 会让人昏睡的气体
Halothane. Sleeping gas.
‎你没被迷晕 算你走运
You're lucky it didn't knock you out.
‎他用东西把她拉着走了
He's pullin' her in somethin'.
‎他要是想带小薇离开岛 ‎事情就更复杂了
If he gets her off the island, this will get a lot messier.
‎飞机场和渡轮都关了
Airport and ferry are closed.
‎要坐私人游艇 他就得去海岸
Private vessel. He's headed to the coast.
‎他有领先优势 ‎我得抓紧了 你待在这里
He's got a head start. I gotta move fast. Stay here.
暴风雨过后  再进城
The storm clears, head into town.
当你看到第一个房子时 就打电话给警长
First house you see, call the sheriff.
‎-喂 你要去哪里  ‎-去找我的孩子
-Hey, where are you goin'? -To find my child.
‎你不知道自己在做什么
You don't know what you're doing.
‎如果你拖慢我的速度 ‎我就把你扔下不管
If you slow me down, I will leave you behind.
‎贾克斯 继续走
Jax. Right on.
‎什么都看不到
You can't see shit.
‎我们很接近了 正在穿过山脊
We're close. We're clearing the ridge.
‎我们马上就到
We'll be there shortly.
‎该死的一群白痴
-Fuckin' idiots.
‎不 没关系
No. No, no, no. It's okay.
‎我知道好久没见了
I know it's been a while.
‎也许这能唤起你的记忆
Maybe this'll jog your memory.
‎这个是教堂
Here's the church…
‎这是尖顶
Here's the steeple…
‎把它打开 然后是…
Open it up and…
‎是你
It's you.
‎对 是的 是我
Yes, it is. It's-- it's me.
‎是我 宝贝
It's me, sweetie.
‎你探完险回来了
You came back from your adventure.
‎没错
I sure did.
‎我还给你带了礼物呢
And… and I even brought you a present.
‎是在宝藏堆里找到的吗
Is it part of the treasure?
‎宝藏 对
Uh, treasure? Yeah!
‎没错 当然是了
Yeah, it sure is.
‎而且你和我要一起 ‎去一趟属于我们的探险
And… you and I are gonna go on our own adventure together.
‎妈妈在哪儿 她跟我们一起去吗
Where's Mo-- Where's Mommy? Is she coming with us?
‎对 她当然要去
Yeah, of course she is. Of course she is.
‎我给她留了纸条和提示 让她跟上来
I left her a note and some clues to follow us,
‎她晚点会跟我们汇合的 好吗
and she's gonna meet up with us after, okay?
‎别急嘛
Uh-- Whoa.
‎你要说什么
What do you say?
‎谢谢 爸爸
Thank you, Daddy.
‎好的
-Okay.
‎能收到吗
- Do you copy?
‎收到 快上线 能听到吗
Come on. Get on radio. -Do you copy?
‎好吧 我还有一件事要处理
-All right, I've gotta do one more thing.
‎然后你就要和我一起开始探险了
And then you and I are gonna start our adventure together.
‎所以你戴上这个 好了 就是这样
See, you put these on… All right, like that.
‎好吗
Okay?
‎给你
Here.
‎你看到什么了吗
You see anything?
‎-你认识他们  ‎-托尼和格里 是菲利普的战友
-You know them? -Tony and Gerry. They served with Philip.
‎-他们就跟菲利普一样狠毒 ‎-来吧
They're just as vicious as he is. Come on.
‎趴下别动 你的外套就是一个活靶子
Stay down. Your jacket might as well have a target painted on it.
‎我们等着
-We wait.
‎万一这只是声东击西呢
Suppose this is just a distraction?
‎好争取更多时间让他带着小薇离开 ‎他就喜欢搞这种鬼把戏
Buying him more time to get away with Vee. It's the kind of game he likes to play.
‎拿闪亮的东西在你面前晃
Danglin' somethin' shiny in front of you,
‎然后他趁你不备 给你脑袋一闷棍
and you don't notice when he's about to bash you over your goddamn head.
‎你会用枪吗
Do you know how to use this?
‎我会 我离开他之后去上课学过
Mmm, yeah. -I took lessons after I left him.
‎好的 我得去看一下
-All right, I'm gonna go have a look.
‎如果有人离得太近 就用这个
If anybody gets too close, use this.
‎直接戳眼睛 眼瞎的人没法要你的命
Go for the eyes. A man can't kill what he can't see.
‎-你在哪里学的这些东西  ‎-女童子军
-How do you know all this? -Girl Scouts.
‎贾克斯 待着别动
Jax. Stay.
‎这种鬼天气 没人想跟着他过来
All right, no one's gonna follow him in this shit.
‎感觉这又是一次菲利普的蹩脚游戏
I'm telling you, this feels like another one of Philip's fucked-up games.
‎有人吗
Hello?
‎不好意思 我把这里都转了个遍
Oh, excuse me. I'm completely turned around out here. I--
‎我在找我家的狗 可怜的小家伙…
I… I was looking for my dog. The poor little guy--
‎-我没看到狗 ‎-好吧
I haven't seen any dogs. Okay.
‎你有电话可以借给我用吗 我只想…
Do… do you have a phone I could use? -I just want--
‎就你一个人
-Are you alone?
‎很不幸 是的
Unfortunately. Um…
‎听我说 我感觉自己 ‎没法再撑三个小时走路回家了
Look, I-- I don't think I can make it the three hours back home, but…
‎不过 要是能歇歇脚就好了
if I could just rest and get my… my bearings?
‎天啊
Christ.
‎好吧 只能待两分钟
-Okay. Just two minutes.
‎非常感谢
Thank you so much.
‎该死
Oh shit.
‎多谢你的善心
Oh, bless your heart.
‎早上好啊
Oh, good morning.
‎她的狗跑丢了 被雨淋湿了
She lost her dog, man. She's soaked.
‎只要让我的血液循环起来就好
Just need to get my blood movin' again.
‎天啊 外面的风暴真是厉害
My goodness. Quite a storm out there.
‎你叫什么名字
What's your name?
‎哦 抱歉 我叫玛莎
Oh, sorry, I'm-- I'm Martha.
‎弗莱明
Flemming.
‎但你们可能认识我丈夫 ‎他上班的地方在…
But you might know my husband, Gordon. -He works at the--
‎不认识
-I don't.
‎来 坐一下吧
Here. Why don't you grab a seat?
‎-让冰冷的脚休息一下 ‎-那就太好了
-Give those cold feet a break. -They sure could use it.
‎谢谢
Thank you.
‎非常感谢
Thank you so much.
‎你在岛上待了很久吗
So… been on this island long?
‎32年了
-Oh, 32 years.
‎不知道这有什么好的
-I don't get the appeal.
‎过来一趟也麻烦 天气又糟糕
It's a pain in the ass to get to. -Weather's shit.
‎得慢慢习惯才行
It's an acquired taste.
‎我就很喜欢这里
I love it, though.
‎我倒觉得是个藏身的好地方
-Good place to hide, I reckon.
‎得了吧 托尼 放松点 她只是个老太
Come on, Tony, relax. She's just an old lady.
‎（来自德黑兰的爱）
‎这汤闻着好香啊
The soup smells so good.
‎这里真舒服 又暖和
So nice and warm in here.
‎那一定是我家贾克斯
That must be my Jax.
‎坐下 玛莎
Sit down, Martha.
‎他要带她去哪里
Where is he taking her?
‎快说
Where…
‎他要带她去哪里
…is he taking her?
‎老鹰湾
Eagle Bay.
‎然后呢
And then where?
‎我不知道
I don't know.
‎我发誓 我只知道这些
I swear. That's all I know.
‎你要开枪打我吗
You gonna shoot me?
‎事态
Things, uh…
‎更严峻了
escalated.
‎贾克斯 我是怎么跟你说的
Jax. What'd I tell you about that?
‎在你杀格里之前 ‎他说了关于小薇的线索吗
Gerry, he say anything about Vee before you killed him?
‎一个字都没说
Not a word.
‎给你 把这个拿出去 仔细翻一下
Here. Take this outside. Go through it.
‎喂 拜托
Hello? Come on!
把那个东西关掉
Turn that thing off.
‎-我们也许能联系到警长 ‎-这种天气就别指望了
-We might be able to reach the sheriff. -Not in this weather.
‎更有可能会引起菲利普的注意
More likely it'll tip off Philip.
‎-哪个频道才是… ‎-别跟我争辩 快放下
-What channel would the emergency-- -Don't argue with me. Leave it.
‎难以置信
Unbelievable.
‎你知道 我也参加过女童子军
You know, I was in the Girl Scouts, too.
‎我拿到了射箭徽章 ‎交到了笔友 学会了急救
Got my archery badge, pen pal, first aid.
‎但是他们没教过徒手搏击 ‎或者拿家用物品来杀人
There wasn't one for hand-to-hand combat or murder with household objects.
‎是吗 那肯定是我服役的时候学的
Really? Must've just been my troop, then.
‎你隶属哪支部队
What branch of the military were you in?
‎中情局
CIA.
‎做了26年的外勤
26 years in the field.
‎间谍
A spy?
‎-还真没想到 ‎-要是被你猜到 我这特务就太菜了
-Wouldn't have guessed that. -Be a shit spy if you did.
‎来吧 贾克斯
-Come on, Jax.
‎爸爸
-Daddy?
‎我在呢
-Yeah!
‎我要尿尿
I need to pee.
‎你能忍一忍吗
-Can-- can you hold it?
‎忍不住了
-Nuh-uh.
‎好吧
-Okay.
‎稍微歇一会儿
Short break.
‎有人吗
-Hello?
‎见鬼
Damn it.
‎喂 有人在吗
Hello, hello. Is anyone there?
‎我们快走
Let's go!
‎好了 快点 小薇
Okay, come on, Vee.
‎小薇
Vee?
Vee!
‎让我看看
Let me see?
‎是的 它的翅膀受伤了 小薇
Yeah. No, he's got-- he's got a bad wing, Vee.
‎对
Yeah.
‎你要知道
You know…
‎有时候在大自然里
sometimes, in nature, when a…
‎当一个生物受伤了
creature's damaged…
‎其实你也救不了它
there's nothing you can do to save them.
‎就好像它注定要死亡
It's almost like they were meant to die.
‎但也许它只是累了
But maybe he's just tired.
‎也许吧 是的
Maybe. Yeah.
‎来 我把它放到这上面
Uh… Here. We'll put him right up here.
‎-好了 来吧 ‎-等等 我还没尿尿呢
-All right. Come on. -Wait, I haven't peed yet.
‎快点 小薇 得走了
Come on, Vee. Now!
‎妈的
Fuck!
‎-操 ‎-哪里疼
-Fuck. -What's hurtin'?
‎不疼
Nothin'.
‎快点 我们得继续走
Come on. We gotta keep movin'.
‎妈的 开什么玩笑 见鬼 我操
-Fucking kidding me! Damn it. Fuck!
‎嗨 得下来自己走了 好吗
Hi. We have to walk now, okay?
‎-我需要休息一下 ‎-啊
-I need a break. -Huh?
‎我需要休息 暖暖身子
I need a break to warm up.
‎没时间了 卢
No time, Lou.
‎他也会休息 ‎从他留下的踪迹就看得出来 来吧
He takes breaks too. I can tell by the tracks. Come on.
‎该死
Oh, God damn it!
‎可恶
Oh shit.
‎我不觉得太冷
I'm not too cold.
‎你呢
You?
‎该死
Shit.
‎你带伤走了这么久 早该告诉我才对
You walked a long way on that. You should've said somethin'.
‎好让你抛下我不管
And give you an excuse to abandon me?
‎-那是给我的吗  ‎-不是
Is that for me? No.
‎能给我一点吗
Well, can I have some?
‎谢谢
Thanks.
‎你却还是留下了
And yet you stayed.
‎你早就该做点什么了
Well, should've done somethin'.
‎是啊
Yeah.
‎谢谢你 卢 你这番话很有帮助
Thanks, Lou. That's… very helpful.
‎我是说你应该早点离开他
Just saying you could've left him sooner.
‎你知道跟他这样的人 ‎在一起是怎样的吗
What is it you know about being with someone like him?
‎所以或许不要当事后诸葛
So maybe don't tell me what I should have done.
‎我都不认得跟他在一起时的自己
I didn't recognize who I was with him.
‎其实 我以为我可以治愈他
I actually felt I could fix him.
‎你知道 我们最初认识时 他很爱我
You know, when we met, he was loving,
‎他很在乎我 但他的心支离破碎
he was caring… But so broken.
‎过去这么久了 ‎我还以为都是我一个人的错
For so long, I thought… thought it was all me.
‎我以为…
I thought…
‎为什么我会让他失望
"Why am I failing him?
‎为什么我的爱还不够
Why isn't my love enough?"
‎我不知道
I don't know.
‎那个混蛋是个怪物
That son of a bitch is a monster.
‎不管是什么炼狱把他折磨成这副模样
Whatever the hell made him this way.
‎反正就算用尽全世界的爱
There ain't no amount of love in this entire world
‎都没法拯救他这种人
that's gonna be able to save that man.
‎他伤害过小薇吗
He ever hurt Vee?
‎没有
No.
‎还没有
Not yet.
‎每当他大发脾气的时候
When he would get into his moods,
‎我就跟小薇小声说：“游戏开始”
I'd whisper to her, "Game on,"
‎然后她就会跑去躲起来
and she'd run and hide.
‎我居然把它变成了一个该死的游戏
Actually made it into a… a goddamn game.
‎你说这有多可悲
How pathetic is that?
‎他总是说 如果我带走小薇 ‎他就会杀了我们两个
He always said, if I took Vee away, he'd kill us both.
‎所以你说吧 我当时该怎么办
Go on… Tell me what I should've done.
‎我想我俩都经历了别人无法理解的事
I guess we've all been through things other people will never understand.
‎汉娜
Hannah?
‎我们会把她救回来的
We'll get her back.
‎来吧
Come on.
‎该死
Oh, shit, shit, shit, shit.
‎慢慢来 保持平稳
-Slow and steady.
‎回家吧 贾克斯
Home, Jax.
‎不准跟我争辩 回家 快去
No arguments. Home. Now!
‎见鬼
Oh shit.
‎他到底是怎么带着小薇一起过去的
How the hell did he do this with Vee?
‎-得爬过去才行 ‎-该死
Gotta climb around it. Oh shit.
‎哇
-Whoa!
‎来吧
Come on!
‎我扶着你
I got you.
‎很好
Good job.
‎该死
Shit.
‎天啊
Jesus.
‎真会挑时候 妈的
Not now. God damn it.
‎-卢 你怎么了  ‎-没什么
-Lou, what's the matter? -Nothing.
‎卢
-Lou!
Lou!
‎谢天谢地
-Oh, thank God.
‎你让我扶你起来就好了嘛
I can help you if you just let me.
‎不需要你帮我
I don't need your help.
‎妈的
-Oh, fuck!
‎起来 耽误了一小时 得追上他
Get up. We just lost an hour on him.
‎喂 我叫你不要带上这玩意儿
Hey, I told you to leave that behind.
‎风暴过去了 ‎我要爬上那个山顶 试着连接
Storm's passed. I'm gonna climb up to that hilltop. -Try to connect.
‎没时间了
-There's no time.
‎见鬼 你别那么固执好吗  ‎我们需要帮助
God damn it. Can you stop bein' so stubborn? We need help.
‎没人能帮我们 ‎我是你的唯一希望 现在继续走吧
-There is no one who can help us. -Shit. -I'm all you've got. Now keep movin'.
‎-你为什么要帮我 卢  ‎-老鹰湾就在前面
-Why are you helpin' me, Lou? -Huh? -Eagle Bay's just ahead.
‎-别拖慢我的速度 ‎-见鬼
-Don't slow me down. -God damn it.
我们错过了
We missed them.
‎海浪这么汹涌 人员无法进出
No one's comin' or goin' in water this rough.
‎那他打算怎么办
-Then what's his plan?
‎这边
-Over here.
‎小薇
-Vee!
Vee!
‎汉娜
Hannah.
‎-你把她带到哪里去了  ‎-别喊了
-Where did you take her? -Stop.
‎他这是在捉弄你
-He's fucking with you.
‎我们可以就这样耗一天
We can do this all day.
‎也许你说得对 ‎我们可能确实需要帮助
Maybe you're right. Maybe we do need help.
‎你回到山里去
Go back to that hill.
‎看看你能不能联系上兰金 ‎紧急服务在第16频道
See if you can raise Rankin. Emergency services are channel 16.
‎联系到了之后回来这里跟我汇合
Meet me back here when you're done.
‎谢谢你
Thank you.
‎你打算怎么办
What are you gonna do?
我需要休息
I need to rest.
快去
Go on.
‎嘿 等一下
Hey, hold up.
‎可别一枪崩了自己的脑袋
Try not to blow your brains out.
‎（永远和你在一起 ）
‎（你照亮我的生活）
‎好了
There we are.
‎冻结在时间里
Frozen in time.
‎永远和你在一起
Together forever.
‎还想再印一个吗
Wanna do another one?
‎你知道吗
Did you know…
‎世界各地的山洞里都有像这样的手印
that there are handprints like these in caves all over the world?
‎等你和妈妈还有我都死了很久之后
And long after you and Mommy and I are all dead…
‎这些手印还会在这里
these handprints are still gonna be here.
‎有人吗
Hello?
‎喂 有人能听到吗
Hello? Can anyone hear me? Hello?
‎有人听到吗
Can anybody hear me?
‎喂
Hello?
‎你好 有人吗
Hello, anybody?
-该死 -我是兰金‎警长
-God damn it. -This is Sheriff Rankin.
你是谁 结束
Who is this? Over.
‎警长 兰金警长
Sheriff! Sheriff Rankin.
这是--这是汉娜·道森
This is-- this is Hannah Dawson.
‎-…被绑架了 ‎-绑架
…kidnapped. Kidnapped?
汉娜 你能听到我说话吗
Hannah, can you hear me?
请重复一遍好吗
Can you repeat that, please?
好的
Uh-- Okay.
我女儿被她父亲绑架了
My daughter was kidnapped by her father.
我...
I'm…
‎-卢阿德尔和我在一起 ‎-汉娜 你能确认情况吗
Lou Adell is with me… Hannah, can you please confirm?
‎-汉娜道森 你能听到吗  ‎-什么
Hannah Dawson? Can you hear me? What?
‎你再说一次好吗
Say that… say that again?
‎拜托
-Come on, come on, come on.
‎警长
Sheriff?
‎该死 好吧
Oh fuck. Okay…
‎可恶
Shit.
‎呼叫托瑞斯
Torres, come in.
‎-警长 请讲 ‎-听着 我们有情况
-Go, Sheriff. -Listen, we got a situation.
‎听起来难以置信
This is gonna sound a bit crazy,
‎但是我想汉娜道森的女儿 ‎被她父亲绑架了
but I think Hannah Dawson's daughter has been kidnapped by… by her father.
‎什么
What?
‎听着 我们马上把信息发布出去
Listen, let's put it on the wire, right away,
‎以防女孩被带离这座岛
in case she's taken off the island.
‎好吧 汉娜道森 薇道森和卢阿德尔 ‎她好像也提到了卢
Okay? Hannah and Vee Dawson and Lou Adell. I think she mentioned Lou.
‎放下枪
The guns.
‎慢点
Slowly.
‎你好 菲利普
Hello, Philip.
‎别担心她
Don't worry about her.
‎我已经确保她会保持昏睡
I've made sure she'll sleep through this.
‎告诉我一件事 老实回答
Just tell me one thing. And be honest here.
‎你为什么要出卖我
Why'd you sell me out?
‎我知道你迟早会找到汉娜和小薇
I knew you'd track down Hannah and Vee sooner or later.
‎我无法永远保护她们
I wasn't gonna be able to protect them forever.
‎保护她们 这一切都是因你而起
Protect them? All of this is happening because of you.
‎不是吗 汉娜可能太天真了 ‎她没想明白 但是我不傻
Okay? And Hannah may be too naive to-- to see it, but I don't.
‎汉娜不知道我是谁
Hannah doesn't know who I am.
‎你连承认我是你儿子都还做不到
You still can't even admit I'm your son.
‎菲利普 你打算做什么  ‎为什么要这样你追我赶
So what's the plan, Philip? Why the elaborate chase?
‎为什么要让我们追踪你  ‎你并不想伤害你的孩子
Why let us track you? You don't wanna hurt your kid.
‎你知道吗 那些人把我掳走时 ‎我年纪就跟小薇一样
Did you know that Vee is the same age as I was when those-- those men took me?
‎是的 但他们就没有 ‎像我现在这样 对她这么温柔了
Yeah, but they weren't as nice as, uh… as I'm being to her.
‎这样的相似程度 你不觉得很巧吗
Can you appreciate that? The symmetry of that?
‎我以为我妈妈也会回来救我
I thought my mommy was comin' back to save me, too.
‎那是个陷阱 ‎要是我来救你的话 我俩都会被抓
It was a trap. If I'd tried to save you, they would have had us both.
‎胡说 你只想保护自己的卧底身份
Bullshit. You wanted to maintain your cover.
‎我只是你执行任务的一枚棋子而已
I was a pawn for your mission. Nothin' else.
‎我救了你 我把你从伊朗救了出来
-I had you rescued. I got you out of Iran.
‎那你怎么不跟我一起回来  ‎原因很简单
-Then why didn't you come back with me? Here's why.
‎因为你他妈的选择了中情局 ‎而不是选择自己的孩子
Because you chose the fucking CIA over your own child.
‎后来事情怎么样
Yeah, how'd that work out for you? Hmm?
‎伊朗被你们搞得一团糟 ‎你们还做过比这更糟糕的事吗
I mean, did you guys fuck up anything worse than you fucked up Iran?
‎然后 你偷走了我的妻子和孩子…
And then you steal my wife and-- and my kid--
‎她们跟我犯的错无关 别牵扯上她们
Hannah and Vee had nothing to do with my mistakes. Leave them out of this.
‎你就别给我上思想道德课了
Oh, spare me the fuckin' morality lesson.
‎你早就放弃了这个权利
You gave up that right a long time ago.
‎现在还不迟
It's not too late.
‎你敢动一下 我就给你一枪
You move, I'mma put a bullet in you.
‎现在还不迟
It's not too late.
‎把小薇留给我 然后你走吧
Leave Vee with me and go.
‎我会把她们从你的踪迹中抹去
I'll throw them off your trail.
‎菲利普 听我说
Philip, listen to me.
‎你说得对
You're right.
‎你小时候我没保护好你 ‎现在就让我做弥补吧
I didn't protect you when you were a kid. So let me do it now.
‎闭嘴
Shut up.
‎怎么 你想杀我
What, you wanna kill me?
‎动手吧
Do it.
‎你昨晚带走小薇时 ‎我正拿着来复枪抵着自己脑袋
Before I knew you took Vee last night, I had my rifle pressed against my head.
‎我不怕死
I'm not afraid to go.
‎你别总是打乱我的思绪 好吗
You just can't stop messin' with my head, can't you?
‎我甚至不知道从何讲起
Kid, I wouldn't even know where to start.
‎我知道你把自己炸死了之后 ‎我就知道时机到了
The minute I heard you blew yourself up, I knew it was time.
‎我以为汉娜和小薇会很安全 ‎我的任务已经完成了
I thought Hannah and Vee were safe. My mission was complete.
‎但你欺骗了我
But you tricked me there, didn't you?
‎你向来都比我聪明
You always were smarter than me.
‎你五岁时下象棋就比我厉害很多
Beat my ass at chess when you were five years old.
‎记得吗
Remember that?
‎我记得
I do.
‎哦 菲利普
Oh, Philip.
‎你猜怎么着
You know what?
‎这次要按我的游戏规则来玩
For once, we're playin' my game.
‎是时候做个了结了
It's time to end this legacy.
‎好让这一家子都摆脱痛苦
Put this whole family out of its misery.
‎菲利普 你是她爸爸
Philip, you're her father.
‎你也是我妈妈啊
And you're my mother.
‎妈妈
Mom! Mom!
‎我们会在灯塔等你
We'll be waiting for you at the lighthouse.
‎一定要带汉娜一起来
Make sure you bring Hannah.
‎别让我们久等
Don't take too long.
‎妈的
Fuck.
‎只是想问问你情况怎么样
Just checking in on ya. How are you doing out there?
‎副警长 进展如何
-Talk to me, Deputy.
‎在全境通缉布告里没找到匹配
-Still no hits on the APBs.
‎已把卡车上的炸弹告知了交通运输部 ‎跟验尸官汇报了尸体情况
I notified ATF about the bomb in the truck and the coroner about the body.
‎等天气好转 他们就会派队伍过来
They're sending teams when the weather lets up.
‎奥卡斯岛警察局
Orcas Island Sheriff's Department.
‎是的 长官
Yes, sir.
‎警长 是联邦执法官
Sheriff, it's the federal marshals.
‎我是兰金 你是哪位
-This is Rankin. Who's this?
‎警长 我是多米尼克科朗 ‎你收到传真了吗
-Sheriff, Dominick Crown here. Did you receive our facsimile transmission?
‎收到了 我正拿在手里
Yeah, I got it right here.
‎我们在全境通缉布告里 ‎看到了你们所说的卢阿德尔
We've seen the APB for the woman you know as Lou Adell.
‎她跟照片里的这个人相匹配吗
Is she a match for the person in that photo?
‎对 是啊 看起来像是她
Yeah. Yeah, it sure looks like her.
‎-你能确信是她吗 警长  ‎-就是她
-How confident are you, Sheriff? It's her.
‎那第二个人呢
-And the second individual?
‎等一下
-Hang on one second.
‎你认得他吗
Do you recognize him?
‎不认得 你是说这家伙也牵涉其中
No. Are you telling me that this guy is involved?
‎你知道这些人所处的位置吗
Do you have any intel on the location of these individuals?
‎-他们是不是在一起  ‎-我不知道
-Are they together? Well, I don't know if they're together.
‎我想他们要去老鹰湾 位于岛的西侧
What I believe is that they're headed to Eagle Bay, on the west side of our island.
‎我们必须确保没有平民前往那附近
We need to make sure no civilians go anywhere near that location.
‎设置路障 封锁该区域
Set up roadblocks and cordon the area.
‎还有个被绑架的小女孩 ‎她妈妈也在那里
There's a kidnapped girl and her mother out there.
‎-你等一会儿 ‎-什么
-Hold. -Excuse me?
‎这混蛋居然让我等着 难以置信
Asshole put me on hold. Unbelievable.
太他妈不可思议了
Un-fuckin'-believable.
兰金警长
Sheriff Rankin?
‎对 就是我
- Yeah, right here.
‎那个男性逃犯是美国特种部队的
The male fugitive is US Army Special Forces,
‎因多起谋杀平民案而被定罪
convicted in the murder of numerous civilians.
‎那个女性是中情局的重点通缉目标
The female is a high-priority target for the CIA.
‎中情局 卢阿德尔
The CIA? Lou Adell?
‎这项调查现在由美国执法官负责
This investigation is now under the jurisdiction of the US Marshals.
‎已获授权使用致命武力
Lethal force has been authorized.
‎禁止任何人进入老鹰湾 ‎你们部门的人不准…
Do not allow any approach to Eagle Bay. -Not by your department, not--
那里有一个被绑架的女孩和她的母亲
There-- there is a kidnapped girl and her mother out there.
‎别干扰我们执行任务 警长
Stay out of our way, Sheriff.
‎（急救箱）
‎卢 抱歉 我来晚了
Lou, sorry it took me so long.
‎我试着尽量往高处爬 但是…
I tried to get as high as I could, but…
‎天啊 见鬼
-Jesus. Oh shit.
‎天啊 好 等等 我来帮你
Oh God, oh God, oh God. Okay, wait, wait. Let me help. Let me help.
‎是他干的吗
-Did he do this?
‎小薇呢 她没事吧
And Vee? Is she… is she all right?
‎她暂时没事 他把她带去灯塔了
She's okay for now. He's taking her to the lighthouse.
‎动作要快
Do it quick--
‎我正在弄
-I'm trying.
‎尽量用纱布填满它
Fill it with gauze. As-- as much as you can.
‎-该死 ‎-来吧 深入一点 把伤口包紧了
-Oh shit. -Come on, deeper. -Really pack it in.
‎我正在弄 天啊 卢 ‎很抱歉 我把你拉下这趟浑水
-I'm trying. -Jesus, Lou. -I'm so sorry I dragged you into this.
‎把手放在这里 用力按 我去拿些胶布
Put your hand here. Right. Press down. Okay, good. I gotta-- I gotta grab some tape.
‎你联系上警长了吗
Hannah. Did you reach the sheriff?
‎-我也不确定 ‎-先别管了
-Uh, I don't know. -Leave it.
‎-等等 ‎-不用了
-Wait, uh-- -It's fine.
‎是我在小屋里找到的 ‎我原本想告诉你的
I found those at the cabin. I meant to tell you.
‎你在说谎
You're lying.
‎（嗨 妈妈 轮到我啦）
‎这个留言不是给我的 对吧
This message isn't for me, is it?
‎都不是给我的
None of them are.
‎你说吧
Say it.
‎我要你亲口说出来
I need you to say it.
‎说啊
Say it!
‎他是我儿子
He's… my son.
‎我之前驻扎在伊朗
When I was stationed in Iran,
‎当时我必须接近一个极度危险的人物
I had to get close to a very dangerous man.
‎关系很亲密
-Very close.
‎不是吧
No, no, no, no.
‎我留着孩子是为了掩护我的卧底身份
I kept the baby to keep my cover.
‎你是说菲利普吗  ‎你的孩子 你是说你的儿子
You mean… you mean Philip? The baby? You mean your son?
‎所以是怎么回事 在玩游戏
So what is this? Some game?
‎你在捉弄我吗  ‎怎么 是你告诉他我们在这里的吗
You fucking with me? What, you tell him where we were, or… -
‎-不是 ‎-那是什么
-No. What-- what is this?
‎我不是在帮他
I wasn't helping him.
‎-我在帮你和小薇 ‎-别再骗我了
-I was helping you. You and Vee. -Stop lying to me.
‎快他妈的告诉我真相
-Tell me the goddamn truth!
‎是我引你到这座岛上来的
I got you to this island.
‎你大学的老朋友
Your old friend from college?
‎那个人告诉你奥卡斯岛 ‎是个漂亮的世外桃源 房租又便宜
The one who told you about the beautiful secluded place on Orcas Island with the cheap rent?
‎是我让她在街上假装偶遇你的
I had her run into you on the street.
‎我原本想阻止菲利普
I tried to stop him.
‎于是我勒索中情局 ‎逼他们调查菲利普在萨尔瓦多的行为
I blackmailed the CIA to force an investigation into what he did in El Salvador.
‎你以为是你救了我们
-You think you saved us?
‎我知道他最终会追踪到你
-I knew he'd track you eventually.
‎你没有救我们
You didn't save us.
‎是我带着小薇离开了他
I got Vee away from him.
‎我每天都照顾她 确保她的安全
I took care of her every goddamn day and made sure she was safe.
‎就因为你 现在害小薇落在了他手上
Now she's out there with him because of you.
‎你根本不是英雄  ‎你他妈的是个胆小鬼
You're no damn hero. You're a fucking coward.
‎-这… ‎-那个男人的所有愤怒
-Wow. -All that rage that that man felt.
‎他心里燃烧的全部怒火
All the rage inside of that man that he felt,
‎撒在我身上的怒气 ‎全都是你一手造成的
that he aimed towards me, is because of you.
‎不是每个人都适合当母亲
Not everybody is meant to be a mother.
‎是啊 也许吧
Yeah, maybe not.
‎但你原本可以更有人性
But you could have been a little more human.
‎你每天都开车经过我们的拖车
You drove past our trailer every day.
‎卢 你开车经过自己的孙女
You drove past your own granddaughter, Lou.
‎你都没跟她说话 ‎你一句话都没跟她说过
You didn't talk to her. You didn't speak to her.
‎你连看都没看她一眼
You didn't look at her.
‎什么样的人才会这样对待自己家人
What kind of person could do that to their own family?
‎拜托 我们得继续走了
Come on. We gotta keep moving.
‎再也没有“我们”了
There ain't no more "we."
‎汉娜 你不知道他们要去哪里
Hannah, you don't know where they're going.
‎你说了去灯塔 我会沿着海岸走过去
You said the lighthouse. I'll follow the coastline.
‎不要独自过去 这是陷阱
Not on your own. It's a trap.
‎求你了 至少这件事是我在行的
-Please. There's one thing I'm good for.
‎恐怕不是了
-Not anymore.
‎你只会拖慢我的速度
You'll just slow me down.
‎贾克斯
-Jax.
‎卢
-Lou!
‎你没事吧
Are you okay?
‎没想过见到你居然会觉得高兴
Never thought I'd be excited to see you.
‎凡事都有第一次 汉娜在哪儿
-First time for everything. -Where's Hannah?
在去灯塔的路上
On her way to the lighthouse.
‎她的女儿呢
And her daughter?
‎已经在那里了
-Already there with the… -Okay.
‎跟绑匪在一起
…the kidnapper.
‎他有武器
He's armed.
‎非常危险
Very dangerous.
‎联邦调查局也是这样描述你的
That's exactly what the feds said about you.
‎你留在这里 ‎等道路畅通之后 我会派人来救你
You stay here. I'll send someone for you as soon as the road's clear.
‎等等 天啊 先救我出去 ‎我在这里快喘不过气了
Wait. For fuck's sake, help me outside. I'm suffocating in here.
‎来吧
-Come on.
‎我来扶你
I got this.
‎卢 你要告诉我 ‎为什么中情局要找你吗
You gonna tell me why the CIA's lookin' for you, Lou?
‎我用了手里掌握的一些证据
I used some evidence I held onto.
‎什么证据
-What kind of evidence?
‎证明中情局参与了伊朗政变的文件
Documents. Proving CIA involvement in the coup in Iran.
‎我明白为什么他们很生气了 ‎卢 他们正在赶过来
I can see why they'd be pissed about that. -Lou, they're on their way.
‎见鬼 他们可不在乎殃及无辜
Fuck, they won't care about collateral damage.
‎你得把汉娜和小薇救出去
You gotta get Hannah and Vee out of there.
‎这伤口又崩开了 我会失血过多的
This thing starts up again, I'm gonna bleed out.
‎你能去拿急救箱吗 我落在里面了
Will you get the first-aid kit? I left it in there.
‎好
Okay.
‎卢
Lou! Lou!
‎开什么玩笑
You gotta be kidding me.
‎卢
Lou!
‎妈妈
Mommy!
‎-妈妈  ‎-小薇
-Mommy! -Vee!
‎快来 求你了 快来
-Come! Please, come!
‎-小薇  ‎-我在这里 妈妈
-Vee! -I'm here, Mama!
‎-在上面  ‎-我来了
-Up here! -I'm coming!
‎宝贝
Baby?
‎妈妈
-Mommy!
‎嗨 妈妈
Hi, Mommy.
‎嗨 宝贝
Hi, baby.
‎我们还担心你不会出现呢 对吧
We were afraid you weren't gonna show up. Weren't we, Vee?
‎你没事吧
You okay?
‎她当然没事 她和她爸爸在一起
Of course she's okay. She's with her daddy.
‎过来抱抱妈妈
Come, give Mommy a hug.
‎嘿 卢怎么样了 她过来了吗
Hey, how's-- how's Lou doin'? Is she-- Is she on her way?
‎天啊 瞧瞧我
Jesus, look at me.
‎这么多年了 我还在等我妈妈回来
Still waitin' for my mommy to come back after all these years, huh?
‎但我们确实需要等她来 了结这件事
But we do need her here to finish this.
‎我想给妈妈一个拥抱
I wanna give Mommy a hug.
‎菲利普 拜托
Philip, please.
‎求你了 爸爸
Please, Daddy?
‎好的 小薇
Okay, Vee.
‎反正我们也在等卢 那就抱一下吧
One quick hug while we wait for Lou.
‎我好想你啊
Oh, I missed you so much.
‎游戏开始
Game on.
‎爸爸 我能去洗手间吗
Daddy, may I go to the bathroom?
‎当然可以 小薇
Of course you can, Vee.
‎但是上完就立刻回来 好吗
But hey… Come right back, okay?
‎哇 卢对你的影响真不小嘛
Wow, Lou is really rubbin' off on you.
‎来 把枪给我 ‎我们都知道你不会开枪打我的
Come on, just give me the gun. We both know you're not gonna shoot me.
‎你不了解我 菲利普
You don't know me, Phil.
‎-你从来都不了解 ‎-是吗
You never did. No?
‎如果你要开枪打我 几年前就动手了
I know that if you were gonna shoot me, you would have done it years ago.
‎我知道你跟我和卢不一样
I know that you're not like Lou and me.
‎你不是这种人
You're not.
‎换作是她 早就开枪了
Yeah, 'cause she would've shot me already.
‎来吧 把枪给我
Come on. Give me the gun.
‎你抛弃了我
You abandon me,
‎偷走了我的孩子 现在还开枪打我
and then you steal my baby from me, and now you shoot me?
‎你的话对我无效  ‎我不会再上你的当了 菲利普
That shit won't work on me. Not gonna work on me anymore, Phil.
‎我已经不怕你了
I'm not afraid of you anymore.
‎我不会让你像伤害我一样伤害我女儿
And I won't let you hurt my little girl the way you hurt me.
‎汉娜
-Hannah!
‎你还记得吗
Do you remember?
Do you remember…
‎感觉如何
how it felt?
‎小薇 我们得跑了
Vee! We have to run!
‎小薇
Vee!
‎该死
Oh shit.
‎小薇
Vee?
‎游戏结束了 好吗 来 小兔子
Game's over, okay? Come here, Little Rabbit.
‎我们现在就得走了
We gotta go right now.
‎他有没有伤害你 他没伤害你吧
Did he hurt you? He didn't hurt you, right?
‎躲起来
Oh! Hide. Hide. Hide.
‎卢
Lou.
‎-汉娜 ‎-快来
-Hannah. -Come on.
‎我们得走了
-We need to move.
‎小薇
-Vee?
‎-我的枪 ‎-弄丢了
-My gun. -Lost it.
‎-刀呢  ‎-插到菲利普的手上了
-Knife? -Stuck in Philip's hand.
‎试试从舱口出去 快去
Try that hatch. Go, go, now.
‎等等 你的外套卡住了
-Wait, your jacket's stuck.
‎该死
-Oh fuck.
‎把你推上去
Push you up.
‎你得跑到海滩尽头 有多快就跑多快
Run to the end of the beach. Run as fast as you can.
‎-别离开我 ‎-我会来找你 我们爬不出去
-No! -I'll meet you there. -Don't leave me.
‎现在快跑 去吧 小兔子 快跑
We won't fit. You gotta run now. Go, go, go, go. Run, Little Rabbit! Run!
‎都混在一起了 没法拆弹
It's rigged. I can't defuse it.
‎如果改变频道 或许能争取一点时间
Could buy us some time if I can change the frequency.
‎你要去哪里
-Wait. Where are you going?
‎咱俩当中有个真正的女童子军
One of us was actually a Girl Scout.
‎你还带着对讲机吗
-Do you still have the radio? -Yeah.
‎也许终于能派上用场 去把舱口踹开
Maybe we can use it after all. Go bust that gate open.
‎卢
Lou?
‎我们都在这儿
We're all here.
‎我一直希望我们可以一起做这件事
I was hoping that we could all do this together.
‎面对面
-Face to face!
‎好让大家都以恰当的方式做个了结
So that we could end this… the right way.
‎以恰当的方式做个了结
End this right.
‎全家人一起
As a family.
‎整个家庭
‎但有时候你无法一切如愿
But sometimes, you don't get what you want.
‎该死
Fuck!
‎妈的 见鬼
‎操
-Fuck!
‎你他妈的让我进去
Fuck! You fuckin' let me in!
‎该死
Oh shit.
‎-该死 ‎-什么
-Oh shit. -What?
‎中情局出动了
-The CIA's on the hunt.
‎他们来找菲利普还是找你
They comin' for Philip or you?
‎我和菲利普都别想活着出去
They won't want either one of us to leave here alive.
‎去吧
-Go, go.
‎-不 我只会拖慢你的速度 ‎-我不能把你撇下
-No. -I'll just slow you down. -I'm not gonna leave you here.
‎卢 去把你的孙女 ‎带到安全的地方 我会追上来的
Lou, go get your granddaughter to safety. I'll catch up.
‎该死
Fuck!
‎小薇
Vee…
‎过来
Come here.
‎哦
Oof!
‎你是个勇敢的小女孩 你知道吗
You're a brave little girl. You know that?
‎帮帮我好吗
Good. Help me up, will you?
‎好 听我说
Okay, listen to me.
‎我要你去找一根木棍 好吗
I want you to go grab a stick, okay?
‎尽量找一根最长的 去吧
The longest one you can find. Go, go, go.
‎-妈妈  ‎-嘿 宝贝
-Mommy! -Hey, baby.
‎汉娜 对讲机
Hannah. The radio.
‎在我的口袋里
In my pocket.
‎-来吧 ‎-帮帮我
-Come on. -Help me.
‎快 快走
-All right. -Come on, go, run.
‎汉娜 尽量把它举高点
Hannah, hold this up as high as you can.
‎-你是在求救吗  ‎-对
-Are you calling for help? -Yeah.
‎是的 这应该能引起他们的注意
Yeah. That ought to get their attention.
‎你赶紧走
You gotta go.
‎沿着这条路往镇上走 把贾克斯带上
Take the road back towards town.
- 把贾克斯带来 - 你…你和我们一起来
-Bring Jax with you. -You… you come with us.
‎汉娜你要照料好你的孩子
Hannah, you take care of your kid…
‎而我会照料我的孩子
I'll take care of mine.
‎我在家给你留了封信 一定要找到它
I left a letter for you at my house. Make sure you find it.
‎走吧 小薇
Okay. Go on, Vee.
‎可恶
Oh, God damn it.
‎卢 你可别死了
Don't die on me now, Lou.
‎你眼前的就是最重要的一切
Everything that matters is right here in front of you.
‎我知道
I know.
‎去吧 快点
Go. Now!
‎对不起 孩子
I'm sorry, kid.
‎-嘿 小薇 ‎-嘿
-Hey, Vee. -Hey.
‎你好 贾克斯
Hello, Jax.
‎嘿 你现在有两条手链了
Hey, you got two bracelets now.
‎对
Yeah.
‎就像你一样
Just like you.
‎（卢）
‎一条是为了纪念朋友
One's for a friend.
‎她突然就把这房子给了你和你女儿
So, out of the blue, she just leaves you and your daughter this house?
‎是的 这间房子还有很多冷冻鹿肉
Yeah, this house and a ton of frozen deer meat.
‎门没锁
It's open.
‎-嘿 汉娜 ‎-嘿
-Hey, Han. -Hey.
‎你们好
Oh, hello.
‎我们还有几个问题要问道森女士
We had a few more questions for Ms. Dawson here.
希望我没有打扰你
I hope I'm not interrupting.
‎汉娜 验尸官那边有个问题
Hannah, uh, coroner's got an issue.
‎你是亲属 需要你签名 ‎才能给菲利普的遗体放行
You're next of kin. He needs a signature to release Philip's body for burial.
‎抱歉
-Yeah. Sorry.
‎道森女士 卢阿德尔跟你提起过
Ms. Dawson, did Lou Adell ever mention
‎她在中情局任职期间的文件吗
anything about documents from her time in the CIA to you?
‎要是提起过 她这特务就太菜了
She'd be a pretty shit spy if she did.
‎如果你想起任何线索…
If you think of anything…
‎你上次和上上次来的时候给过名片了
You gave me a card last time you were here, and the time before that.
‎任何线索都行
Anything at all.
‎好吧
All right.
‎-警长 告辞 ‎-很高兴又见到你
-Sheriff. -Good to see you again.
‎别管他们
-Forget them.
‎看来你们俩准备好去西雅图了
Looks like you two are ready for Seattle.
‎你都收拾好了
Yeah, you're all packed up.
‎对 差不多
Yeah, almost.
‎我想告诉你 追悼会办得很体面
I wanted to tell you, you just did a beautiful job with the memorial service.
打住  不  是你干的
-Stop. -No, you did.
我想卢会很感激的
And I think Lou would have really appreciated it.
‎得了吧 那些真情吐露只会让她作呕
Come on now. All that sincere emotion would have made her puke.
‎她这人吧…
Oh, well…
‎她确实很有个性
-She was her own person.
‎我是说 有时候我很生她的气 但是
I mean, sometimes, I'm just so damn mad at her, and then…
‎有时候又很想念她
Other times I miss her.
‎对家人的感情不都是这样的吗
Isn't that just how it is with family?
‎我向来不是话多的人 ‎我就长话短说了
"I've never been one for many words, so I'll keep this short."
‎房子归你了 拿去卖掉吧
"The house is yours. Sell it."
‎冰箱的肉够贾克斯吃一个月 ‎还有给你一些现金
"There's a month's worth of meat for Jax in the freezer, and some cash for you."
‎人生没有二次机会 ‎但有时候它允许你重新开始
"Life doesn't give you second chances, but sometimes it does offer a fresh start."
‎汉娜 你会好奇我为什么这么做 ‎为什么把这一切留给你
"Hannah, you're going to wonder why I did it." "Why I left this all for you."
‎简单来说
"The simple answer is,
‎你留给这个世界的东西 ‎会比我留下的东西更美好
you'll leave the world a better place than I did."
‎字幕翻译：杨宇航